<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Serverless Application Model on GPK</title>
    <link>https://www.garrardkitchen.com/tags/serverless-application-model/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Serverless Application Model on GPK</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 11:14:39 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.garrardkitchen.com/tags/serverless-application-model/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Corporate Website</title>
      <link>https://www.garrardkitchen.com/projects/creations/corporate-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 17:31:27 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.garrardkitchen.com/projects/creations/corporate-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Used mainly static content and ported new copy/layout to SAM Serverless Application C# .NET Core Razor Pages solution. Originally WP was in place, so removing MySQL reduced the cost. I created a CI/CD Pipeline using BitBucket.  It is now hosted via API Gateway &amp;amp; Lambda and not via an Azure Website.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Serverless</title>
      <link>https://www.garrardkitchen.com/projects/creations/serverless/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 16:01:53 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.garrardkitchen.com/projects/creations/serverless/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Investigated ways to reduce time to market, end-client license costs, hosting costs and development costs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This research and later development efforts contributed to formulating and maintaining a best practice set of guidelines/principals covering all frameworks and languages employed to deliver a solution [product, automation and integrations].&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Used both Serverless Framework and SAM.  I use several IDEs, dependant on task/requirement, mainly VSCode, Rider, PyCharm and VS.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These are samples of use cases where I have employed Serverless technologies: Websites (ASP.NET Core Razor), major features (utilising full AWS stack), automation (set log retention via CLoudWatch Events, set Log subscription, Set API Gateway Key and store in SSM).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
